MAKSYM SHUMOVYCH

Java/Kotlin Developer



DETAILS

ADDRESS

Kharkiv Ukraine

PHONE

380661135087

EMAIL

nikleft12@gmail.com

LINKS

<u>Linkedin</u>

<u>Github</u>

SKILLS

Java

REST

Kotlin

Spring, Spring Boot, Data, Cloud, Security

SQL, Postgres, Liquibase, Hibernate

Docker

Gardle, Maven, Jenkins

PROFILE

Java/Kotlin developer with 4 years experience. Worked mainly with Spring Framework stack, different REST APIs for mobile apps and tablets, creating and maintaining them with Java and Kotlin. Most interesting thing i have worked with is creating new API for Android and iOS apps for Screwfix - British building goods company. Also worked on American car credit/retailer company to adapt search feature with existing APIs. And one healthcare project.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Kotlin Developer, Capgemini Engineering

Kharkiv

Aug 2023 — Present

- Working with APIs (refactoring old delivering new features)
- Creating and maintain clients to setup SSO via social platforms
- Integrating APIs with healthcare software

Java Developer, EPAM, Cox Automative

Kharkiv

Oct 2022 — Nov 2022

- Implementing search feature with sorting, wiring it with existing API.
- Integrating Fedex in API and barcode reader scan.
- Reverse-engineering existing functionality to define new stories.

Kotlin Developer, EPAM, Screwfix

Kharkiv

Dec 2020 — Oct 2022

- Moving and adapting mobile backend API to tablets.
- Adding new delivery functionality using Gophr to mobile app.
- Defining stories to implement for team.
- Investigating some architectural issues, or ways to create new features.
- Developing core API and wiring it with downstream apps.

Kharkiv

LANGUAGES

English

Kotlin Developer, EPAM, Screwfix, EPAM, Screwfix

Jun 2020 — Dec 2020

- Developing API for downstream ATG API
- Developing sessions service for storing and manipulating information about users sessions via JWT tokens and own session implementation objects
- Managing caches for data obtained from ATG API
- Obtaining and parsing Bazaarvoice product reviews information
- Changing implementation of API on ATG side (CWS API)

Junior Java Developer, EPAM

Kharkiv

Sep 2019 — May 2020

- Updating existing document types, matching models.
- Creating rest endpoints for creating/deleting/updating CMS content
- Using backstopJS for visual testing on jenkins slaves.
- Fixing REST response models
- Managing pages and content between envs
- Changing some jobs for automated Selenide test

Junior Java Developer, EPAM

Kharkiv

Mar 2019 — Jun 2019

Creating microservices for calculating products pricing.

All with tightly coupled ATG platform

EDUCATION

Master, Kharkiv National University of Civil Engineering Kharkiv

Sep 2015 — Feb 2020

Computer Science Faculty